

# **MUHAMMAD USMAN HANIF**

CPR # 950152366, Cell: 39847551, 33103982

DOB; 07 Jan.1995 Email: <u>usmanhanif64@gmail.com</u>

Address: Flat # 3, Bldg # 2929, Road # 243, Block No 302, Manama Bahrain

# **CAREER OBJECTIVES:**

I am pleased to be able to offer any prospective employer no less than two years of experience with in the hospitality field. I boast a thorough knowledge of all in-house operations while I a just as adept at dealing with the needs of the client. I have worked for restaurant as well as for hotel. I am also a team player and I hope to develop long-term relationships with employees and senior staff too. I am ideally searching for a platform, which can provide me with room for upward mobility within a friendly environment. I am ready to undergo any additional trainings, guidance from seniors in the organization or qualifications as may be required

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### FEB 2019-DEC 2019 SENIOR FOOD & BEVERAGE SUPERVISOR

THE LE SHANZE HOTEL

10-N Main Blvd, Block N Phase 2 Johar Town, Lahore, Punjab 54000

+92-307-4736653

**Responsibilities:** Plan & Controls the ordering of food and beverages for hospitality property, manage account payables and receivables related to whole process of purchasing.

# OCT2018-JAN 2019 JUNIOR FOOD & BEVERAGE SUPERVISOR

CHICAGO DOWNTOWN

100A First Floor, Chambeli Block, Bahria Town, Lahore, Pakistan

+92-322-7002299

**Responsibilities:** Greet customers and answer their questions related to menu and specials. Take orders from customers and communicating with the kitchen staff.

### MAY 2018-OCT 2019 CAPTAIN WAITER

CHICAGO DOWNTOWN

100A First Floor, Chambeli Block, Bahria Town, Lahore, Pakistan

+92-322-7002299

**Responsibilities:** Daily quality control checks, Inventory monitoring and Placing orders, End-of-day closing operations.

#### NOV 2017 - MAY 2018 HEAD WAITER

CHICAGO DOWNTOWN

100A First Floor, Chambeli Block, Bahria Town, Lahore, Pakistan

+92-322-7002299

**Responsibilities:** Supervisor for dinning room and dinning establishments, managing the fellow waiters.

## JUNE 2015 –AUG 2015 SUMMER INTERNSHIP-FOOD &BEVERAGE

PUNJAB FOOD AUTHORITY PFA, LAHORE

## **KEY SKILLS:**

- 1. Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point)
- 2. The ability to work within a high pressure and is excellent in multi-tasking
- 3. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills, developed through educational and extra curricular activities.
- 4. Highly developed teamwork skills developed through working in teams for academic projects and in organizations later.
- 5. Efficient organizational and managerial skills developed while participating in academic & non-academic activities.
- 6. Languages (English, Urdu, Hindi, Punjabi)

#### **EDUCATION:**

#### 2017 B.Sc. (Hons.) Agriculture

University College of Agriculture, University of Sargodha (1<sup>st</sup> Division) CGPA = 3.27

## 2013 F. Sc. - Pre-Engineering

Punjab College of Science, Sargodha.(1st Division/Grade 'B')

# 2011 S.Sc. - Matriculation in Science Subjects

Fazia Model Inter College Mushaf Sargodha. (1st Division/Grade 'B')

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS:**

- 1. Received EXCELLENCE EMPOLYEE PERFORMANCE Award while working at CHICAGO DOWNTOWN
- 2. Awarded by laptop from Prime minister of Pakistan on the basis of merit.
- 3. Awarded Fouji Foundation Scholarship through out my bachelor's studies at Sargodha University.

4

#### **CONFERENCES & SEMINARS:**

- 1. Participated in an international symposium on <u>STRATEGIES FOR OVERCOMING FOOD SECURITY PROBLEMS THROUGH UTILIZATION OF RAIN-FED AREAS</u> held on 26-28 March 2014 at University of Sargodha Pakistan.
- 2. Participated in one-day workshop on <u>NEW PESTICIDES FORMULATION</u> at Ali Akbar Group of Industries Lahore on 28th Nov. 2016.
- 3. Attended a workshop on <u>INSECT REARING TECHNIQUES IN INSECTARY</u> at National Agriculture Research Centre (NARC) Islamabad, Pakistan on 8<sup>th</sup> Dec. 2016.

# **EXTRA CURRICULAR:**

- 1. Event Manager for university sports festivals.
- 2. Captain of University Football Team and won many inter departmental Football matches held in Sports Gala events.
- 3. Got runner up prize in athletics competition at university level.

**REFERENCES:** Reference can be provided on request.